Translation and modification || Muhammad Al Nuaimi and Dr. Ali Talal
翻译及修改 ||穆罕默德·阿尔·努埃米 (Muhammad Al Nuaimi) 和阿里·塔拉勒 (Ali Talal) 博士
"Libya, Gaddafi's old chemical factory."
“利比亚，卡扎菲的老化工厂。”
Omar, how is the general?
奥马尔，将军怎么样？
.He is still with his family
.他仍然和家人在一起
no?
不？
(Hamza)!
（哈姆扎）！
..(Hamza)
..（哈姆扎）
Be careful!
当心！
Go with them .Take them to the underground shelter
和他们一起去 .带他们到地下避难所
Move! Move!
移动！移动！
They went down!
他们倒下了！
Hey, hey!
嘿嘿！
Where is General Faizan?
费赞将军在哪里？
.Tell me
。告诉我
"Mercenaries"
《雇佣兵》
|| Mercenaries: Part Four ||
||雇佣兵：第四部分||
"United States, New Orleans"
“美国，新奥尔良”
Maybe I'm complicated, but I'm not desperate
也许我很复杂，但我并不绝望
Is that what we call it?
这就是我们所说的吗？
"complicated"?
“复杂的”？
Whatever it's called, it doesn't work, right?
不管它叫什么，它都不起作用，对吗？
Come on, Jenna, you're not meditating .small details
来吧，珍娜，你没有冥想 .小细节
What are the little details? You?
有哪些小细节呢？你？
Are you my little detail?
你是我的小细节吗？
God, my dear, you realize The problem, but you ignore it
上帝，亲爱的，你意识到 问题来了，你却忽略了它
Do you really know what you are? .You're a caveman
你真的知道自己是什么吗？ .你是一个穴居人
-You really look like a caveman -What about you?
-你看起来真的像个穴居人 -你呢？
..You don't want to compete .(Jenna), (Jenna.)
..你不想竞争 .（珍娜），（珍娜。）
Calm down, please - Do you want me to calm down?
请冷静 - 你想让我冷静下来吗？
..Did you just tell me that? Don't tell me to calm down! I am calm
..你刚刚告诉我的吗？ 别告诉我要冷静！我很平静
I have never been so calm in my life More than now!
我一生中从未如此平静过 比现在还多！
,look at me! I'm english" “Absolutely stupid, I don't like to argue
，看着我！我是英国人” “绝对愚蠢，我不喜欢争论
-Guess what? -I just want some peace in life, okay?
-你猜怎么了？ -我只是想要生活安宁，可以吗？
.Be nice -I'm from America. We'll fight about this
。对人好点 -我来自美国。我们会为此争吵
.Go, go -What does this make me?
.走吧，走吧 -这让我做什么？
Does it make me nervous?
这会让我紧张吗？
.no no no
。不不不
.Maybe a little violent
.也许有点暴力
.I am a professional Yes
.我是专业人士 是的
And a little violent - A little
而且有点暴力 - 一点
.this much
。这么多
Do you know what's up?
你知道发生什么事了吗？
I have skills like you and more
我拥有像你一样的技能，甚至更多
Neither of you like that Because you're both cavemen
你们都不喜欢那样 因为你们都是穴居人
.She's talking to you
.她在跟你说话
-Actually, she's looking in your direction -But I'm talking to you
-事实上，她正在看着你的方向 -但我正在跟你说话
What about you?
你呢？
Maybe you're my boss
也许你是我的老板
But I see that you are from this planet Which is called "desperate."
但我看到你来自这个星球 这就是所谓的“绝望”。
Where intimate relationships are Feelings do not exist!
亲密关系在哪里 感情是不存在的！
God, I wasted so much From my life to you
天哪，我浪费了太多 从我的生活到你
-You are a failure, but I like you Thank you
-你是个失败者，但我喜欢你 谢谢
Why are you here?
你为什么在这？
I lost my ring at the bar
我在酒吧丢了戒指
-And I need your help - Excuse me, is that all?
-我需要你的帮助 - 对不起，就这些了吗？
We will not talk?
我们不会说话吗？
Are we done with this conversation?
我们的谈话结束了吗？
conversation"?" It's like a heated chat
对话”？” 就像一场激烈的聊天
!damn it
！该死的
.She's talking to you again
.她又跟你说话了
.It's frustrating No, it's okay
.这很令人沮丧 不，没关系
I like her, Bernie
我喜欢她，伯尼
She's part of the mercenaries, Christmas
她是雇佣兵的一员，圣诞节
Listen, I have a lot of respect Your abilities are immense, indeed
听着，我非常尊重 你的能力确实是巨大的
But you really are a selfish bastard
但你确实是一个自私的混蛋
- Really? .All of us
- 真的吗？ .我们所有人
We must choose this life At the expense of friends or family
我们必须选择这样的生活 以朋友或家人为代价
Are we doing it for the money?
我们这样做是为了钱吗？
This is the definition of depravity
这就是堕落的定义
What do you think of my perspective?
您觉得我的观点怎么样？
.it's good
。很好
..I believe
..我相信
.You are an idiot
。你是个白痴
-You don't believe it In every cell of my body
-你不相信 在我身体的每一个细胞里
Why are we here?
我们为什么在这里？
I lost my ring tonight ,past during a quarrel
今晚我丢了戒指 ,过去吵架时
-And I came here to try to buy it again -Seriously?
-我来这里是为了再次购买它 -严重地？
.Yes, seriously
.是的，说真的
You silly one
你个傻子
I am a fan of superstitions and I like this
我是迷信迷，我喜欢这个
.I feel like I'm missing a finger
.我感觉我少了一根手指
I tried to get it back but this A fool is not willing to negotiate
我试图把它找回来，但是这个 傻子是不愿意谈判的
-Who? .(Jumbo Shrim
-WHO？ .(巨型虾
-Who is he? -You will see
-他是谁？ -你会看见
How's it going, Bernie? Hello, Billy
怎么样，伯尼？ 你好，比利
So how did you lose your most precious possessions?
那么你是如何失去最珍贵的财产的呢？
"Duel of Thumbs"
《拇指对决》
- Do you mean the game “hand drop”? "No, I mean 'thumb duel.'
- 你指的是“hand drop”游戏吗？ “不，我的意思是‘拇指决斗’。
-So. GIVE me your hand - No. "Duel of thumbs"?
-所以。把你的手给我 - 不。“拇指决斗”？
You used to be strong, what happened?
你本来就很坚强，怎么了？
And you were hairy, what happened? Things change
而且你身上长满了毛，这是怎么回事？ 事情会改变的
How's it going, Bernie? - What's new? Is Jumbo Shrim here?
怎么样，伯尼？ - 什么是新的？巨型虾在吗？
.there is a problem
。有一个问题
My friend wants his ring back
我的朋友想要回他的戒指
A bet remains a bet, my brother
赌注始终是赌注，我的兄弟
.You know, no offense, but I miss my ring
.你知道，无意冒犯，但我想念我的戒指
.He will remain where he is
.他将留在原地
.this is unacceptable
。这是无法接受的
.terrible resemblance
.可怕的相似
This is cruel
这太残酷了
Are these guys, Bernie? Yes
这些人是吗，伯尼？ 是的
Now I understand why they call it Jumbo
现在我明白为什么他们称之为 Jumbo
No, the other guy. That man
不，是另一个人。那个人
Did you lose to Santa's helper?
你输给了圣诞老人的帮手吗？
.this is embarrassing
.这很尴尬
.I was drunk
。我醉了
.But you're not drunk now
.但你现在没有醉
Why am I here exactly?
我到底为什么会在这里？
.My back hurts
。我背疼
How long?
多久？
A few weeks ago. I can't lift a fork
几周前。我举不起叉子
I'll do it for you, but if you don't want to I understand if you feel threatened
我会为你做的，但如果你不愿意 如果你感到受到威胁我理解
the threat?
威胁？
Wait
等待
It will make things easier for you
它会让你的事情变得更容易
.traditional
。传统的
I'll take care of this, Thumb
我会处理好这个的，大拇指
.beer please
。啤酒，谢谢
How are you on this beautiful day?
在这个美好的日子里，你还好吗？
Would you rather I call you Jumbo? Or "shreem-shrimp"?
你愿意我叫你珍宝吗？ 还是“虾”？
..if you call me that again
..如果你再这么叫我
.I will cut off your head
.我会砍下你的头
.That's a little harsh, kid
.这有点残酷，孩子
Bernie wants his ring back
伯尼想要回他的戒指
What did you call me?
你叫我什么？
How much do you want to meet him, Yoda? Wait!
尤达，你有多想见见他？ 等待！
.He will stay here, you idiot
.他会留在这里，你这个白痴
.my back
。我的背
..As you see
..如你所见
What we have here is an issue Humility and human kindness
我们这里有一个问题 谦逊和人性的善良
My friend here loves his ring For all his stupid reasons
我的朋友很喜欢他的戒指 由于他所有愚蠢的理由
He will be nice and civil of you Gentlemen, you understand this principle
他会对你友善且有礼貌 先生们，你们明白这个道理吗？
..but since you chose to be
..但是既然你选择了
What's the word, Bernie? Stubborn
伯尼，这个词怎么说来着？ 固执的
.very long
。很长
.Foolish
.愚蠢的
You left me no choice, you idiot
你让我别无选择，你这个白痴
.You're welcome -You have become slow
。不客气 -你变慢了
My turn, you bastard
轮到我了，你这个混蛋
.come on man
.来吧伙计
Come on, cowboy, come on
来吧，牛仔，来吧
Have a beer ready for him when he wakes up
当他醒来时为他准备一杯啤酒
You almost killed me
你差点杀了我
.I thought your back hurts
.我以为你背痛
.It's a miracle, he just recovered
.真是个奇迹，他刚刚康复了
He didn't need a show of love
他不需要秀恩爱
I like spending time with you
我喜欢和你一起度过时光
Next time take me To ride a pony, okay?
下次带我去 骑一匹小马，好吗？
.Good
。好的
Field team, what's the situation?
现场团队，情况如何？
Commander, there are three soldiers They guard the general
指挥官，有三名士兵 他们守护着将军
We will need support .I repeat, wait for support
我们将需要支持 .我再说一遍，等待支持
What exactly does he do?
他到底是做什么的？
No, no, please! no
不，不，拜托！不
How are you, General?
将军，你好吗？
Are my eyes deceiving me? -Why?
我的眼睛在欺骗我吗？ -为什么？
What does Gunner have on his head?
枪手头上长的是什么？
She looks like a sick cat
她看起来像一只病猫
.Cute cats
.可爱的猫
.It looks like a shrub
.它看起来像灌木
Good evening, big guy
晚上好，大佬
Let's talk about the thing that .on your head
我们来谈谈这件事 .在你的头上
- The wig? -Yes, the wig
- 假发？ -是的，假发
The question is...why?
问题是……为什么？
I was talking to a girl online And she loved the '70s look, you know
我在网上和一个女孩聊天 你知道，她喜欢 70 年代的造型
Related to fashion
与时尚相关
Understood. Have you met her yet?
明白了。你见过她了吗？
Why wouldn't I do that? I love mystery
我为什么不这样做呢？我爱神秘
-Understood? -Yes, that makes sense
-明白了吗？ -是的，这是有道理的
-It looks special - True
-看起来很特别 - 真的
-I like it more when he's drunk .I understand. Me too
-我更喜欢他喝醉的时候 。我明白。我也是
.I'm happy for you
.我为你感到高兴
Is this the new guy?
这是新人吗？
Hello, Easy Day
你好，轻松的一天
.good man. Former member of the Special Forces
。好人。前特种部队成员
Hello, Bernie Hello, Izzy
你好，伯尼 你好，伊兹
Is this our sniper?
这是我们的狙击手吗？
.do not worry about that
。不用担心那个
I have a specially designed binoculars To be compatible with eyeglass lenses
我有一个专门设计的双筒望远镜 与眼镜镜片兼容
What?
什么？
Okay, Hawk-Eye, remember that face
好吧，鹰眼，记住那张脸
.Don't get it wrong
.别误会
.You know, don't worry about me
.你知道，别担心我
Who is this man?
这个人是谁？
When you moved away, you hired him He's Gallego's son
当你搬走时，你雇佣了他 他是加莱戈的儿子
I inherited the sense of sight and the heart
我继承了视觉和心灵
And sexual desire from my father
还有我父亲的性欲
.Suppose he doesn't talk as much as his father
.假设他不像他父亲那么爱说话
.It's worse No
.更糟糕的是 不
Doubly so
更是如此
It's going to be a long trip
这将是一次漫长的旅行
I am Galan
我是伽蓝
Is it supposed to mean something?
它应该意味着什么吗？
.It's supposed to mean something Okay, enough nonsense. Look at me
.它应该意味着什么 好了，废话够多了。看着我
Who is this man in the suit? His name is Marsh
这个穿西装的男人是谁？ 他的名字叫马什
I did some work with him before I met you
在认识你之前我和他一起做过一些工作
-He's from the CIA Hey Bernie, how's it going?
-他来自中央情报局 嘿伯尼，怎么样？
How are you, Marsh?
你好吗，马什？
how is your hand?
你的手怎么样了？
Gravity takes effect
重力生效
Welcome to the group
欢迎加群
I am happy to get to know you more Guys, there's an urgent matter
我很高兴能够更多地了解你 各位，有一件紧急的事情
I introduce you to Suwartu Rahmat
我向您介绍苏瓦图·拉赫马特
Former British citizen converted To an arms dealer
前英国公民皈依 给军火商
And he has a private army
他还有一支私人军队
He was hired to steal warheads A nuclear missile for a very dangerous customer
他被雇来偷弹头 为非常危险的客户提供的核导弹
Rumor has it that the agent's name is Ocelot
有传言称这名特工的名字是Ocelot
If those nuclear warheads fall into hands Ocelot, he plans to use it.
如果那些核弹头落入手中 豹猫，他打算用它。
To create international chaos This must not be allowed to happen
制造国际混乱 决不能允许这种情况发生
This is why you came here
这就是你来这里的原因
After you land, you will find Gaddafi's factory ..For old military chemicals in Libya
落地后，你会发现卡扎菲的工厂 ..利比亚的旧军用化学品
I heard it's nice there .at this time of year
我听说那里很好 .每年的这个时候
Your job is to make sure The explosives remain there
你的工作是确保 炸药仍留在那里
Good?
好的？
.That's it. good luck
。就是这样。祝你好运
Bernie, keep them -I will do my best
伯尼，保留它们 -我会尽力而为
"Operation Ocelot."
“豹猫行动”。
When were you going to tell me?
你打算什么时候告诉我？
When you stop messing with your girlfriend
当你不再惹你女朋友的时候
Why is Christmas so angry? About the "Ocelot mission"?
为什么圣诞节如此生气？ 关于“豹猫任务”？
.He's acting like Christmas
.他的表现就像圣诞节一样
.Understood
.明白了
He knows Bernie well
他很了解伯尼
He knows exactly what he can do What he did to eliminate the ocelot
他清楚地知道自己能做什么 他做了什么来消灭豹猫
Who calls himself Ocelot?
谁自称豹猫？
Hired intelligence agency Central (Bernie) years ago
受雇情报机构 中央（伯尼）年前
In order to discover the identity of the name The symbolic ocelot in reality
为了查明姓名的身份 现实中象征性的豹猫
.It was close
.已经很接近了
Then someone ambushed him .He almost killed his entire team
然后有人伏击了他 .他几乎杀死了他的整个团队
.the curse
。诅咒
.Okay
。好的
Some say the ocelot is just a ghost Bernie invented it to cover up his mistakes
有人说豹猫只是一个幽灵 伯尼发明它是为了掩盖他的错误
No way
决不
Ocelot exists. And Bernie will bury him one day
豹猫存在。 伯尼有一天会埋葬他
What happened to your ear, man?
老兄，你的耳朵怎么了？
.Glad you asked this
.很高兴你问这个
.I was a wrestler in college
.我在大学时是一名摔跤手
This is a common complication This sport causes ear injuries
这是一种常见的并发症 这项运动会导致耳朵受伤
...Some blood collects in the ear cartilage
...一些血液聚集在耳软骨中
Come on, big bird
来吧，大鸟
“Get off, you death plotter.” -Don't insult her
“滚开，你这个死亡策划者。” -别侮辱她
We have a successful take-off
我们成功起飞
This was probably my first threesome
这可能是我的第一次三人行
You know what I'm talking about Hey, Toll Road, right?
你懂我在说什么 嘿，收费公路，对吧？
.Listen
。听
Do you know what a “golden shower” is?
你知道什么是“黄金雨”吗？
It's when a woman kneels on top of you She empties her bladder on you
当一个女人跪在你身上的时候 她在你身上排空膀胱
.He's very liberal
.他非常自由
Wow, international pervert
哇哦，国际变态
Do you know what a “golden shower” is?
你知道什么是“黄金雨”吗？
"Sober life"
《清醒的生活》
You seem like the type of person .did that before
你看起来像这样的人 .以前这样做过
Let's stop listening to these losers
让我们停止听这些失败者的话
.I've heard a lot
.我听过很多
.It's time for songs .It's time for music
.听歌的时间到了 .音乐时间到了
-It's old .It's comfortable
-它很旧了 .很舒服
Comfortable? Yes
舒服的？ 是的
.maybe
。或许
.I had an anxiety attack last night
.我昨晚焦虑症发作
- Really? Are you sure? Yes
- 真的吗？你确定吗？ 是的
Did you feel goosebumps? And your heartbeat accelerates?
有没有感觉起鸡皮疙瘩？ 你的心跳加速了吗？
.exactly
。确切地
Take some Xanax And pretend that you are happy with life
服用一些阿普唑仑 假装你对生活很满意
!I am happy
！我很开心
By the way, you are the worst doctor ever
顺便说一句，你是有史以来最差的医生
Maybe Jenna is being too hard on you
也许珍娜对你太严厉了
.It actually calms me down
.它实际上让我平静下来
This is the job No
这就是工作 不
Some men are not meant for that .be in a relationship. Face the facts
有些男人不适合这样做 .处于恋爱关系中。面对事实
.Wrong
。错误的
Maybe you want to die a man A bitter old man, but I don't
也许你想作为一个男人而死 一个苦涩的老人，但我不
.I want to be cheerful, happy
.我要开朗、快乐
But I will come to visit you in the sanatorium
但我会去疗养院看望你
- Do you promise me? .Scouting Department
- 你答应我吗？ .侦察部
Let's see what's going on
让我们看看发生了什么
A girl covered me in hot wax .Forget this
一个女孩把热蜡涂在我身上 。忘掉这个
Where are the explosives? Never!
炸药在哪里？ 绝不！
-Your wife No, my wife! no. Allah is the greatest
-你妻子 不，我的妻子！不。真主是最伟大的
Your son will be next
你的儿子将是下一个
Please, not my son. Please
拜托，不是我儿子。请
.Give me the explosives and I'll do it quickly
.给我炸药，我会很快做的
My son Adam
我的儿子亚当
This is a fact that you cannot change
这是你无法改变的事实
..Give me the explosives or else - Not my son
..给我炸药，否则 - 不是我儿子
The decision is yours Okay. Good
决定权在你 好的。好的
.It's in the control room
.在控制室里
..The safe code is...
..安全代码是...
.eight
。八
.One
。一
.four
.四
.two
。二
.Seven
。七
.wise decision
。明智的决定
Let's wake up the kids
让我们唤醒孩子们
-Are you ready? Yes
-你准备好了吗？ 是的
.East. west - West
。东方。西方 - 西
Where did this come from?
这个是从哪里来的？
.this will be fun
.这会很有趣
We are exposed to fire at the landing area .-Forward
我们在着陆区遭遇火灾 。-向前
He confronted the missile Okay
他面对导弹 好的
Intelligence was wrong
情报有误
!Be creative
！要有创意
.No problem
。没问题
Let's go
我们走吧
.gather. Gathered
。收集。聚集
-Shall I take the lead? No
-我来带头吗？ 不
Take Gunner as cover and you'll be fine
以枪手为掩护，你会没事的
!drop
！降低
Have a happy hunt!
祝您狩猎愉快！
.There's something going on at the weapons factory
.武器工厂出事了
We will handle this
我们会处理这个
We have four vehicles and many soldiers
我们有四辆车和很多士兵
Let's try to reduce their numbers
让我们尝试减少他们的数量
"Jump on this!"
“跳上这个！”
Sir, I have a new means of transportation Excellent
先生，我有一种新交通工具 出色的
Tell Ocelot we got it On explosives
告诉欧斯洛我们找到了 关于爆炸物
!Let's go
！我们走吧
.Positioned on site
.定位于现场
Get in the truck! .(The explosives are in the possession of Rahmat
上卡车吧！ .（爆炸物由拉赫马特拥有
Gunner, do you see them?
枪手，你看到他们了吗？
.clearly
。清楚地
Gunner, you missed the target. Do you need a guide dog?
枪手，你没有击中目标。 您需要导盲犬吗？
.the curse
。诅咒
Stevie Wonder, maybe you should. You should check your glasses
史蒂夫·旺德，也许你应该这样做。 你应该检查一下你的眼镜
Be careful. Where are you, Lee?
当心。李，你在哪里？
.It seems we are on a chase
.看来我们正在追逐
.relax
。放松
Let's fly, my dear!
亲爱的，我们一起飞吧！
Who the hell is this man?
这个男人到底是谁？
What do we do, leader?
领导，我们该怎么办？
.Kill them
。杀了他们
Shoot!
射击！
Gunner, we need some help!
枪手，我们需要帮助！
.I've been sober for six months
.我已经清醒六个月了
This is what I'm talking about, Gunner
这就是我要说的，枪手
Can you get rid of them?
你能摆脱它们吗？
We will chase them! - It is known
我们会追赶他们的！ - 我们都知道
.disperse
。分散
Galan, we'll take the lead. Chase the fugitive
加兰，我们带头。 追捕逃犯
.known
.已知
We lost the 50 caliber machine gun
我们丢失了50口径机枪
.He started from his side
.他从他身边开始
It's time to improvise
是时候即兴创作了
.I can improvise
.我可以即兴发挥
A bullet in the stomach. You will stay alive
肚子里一颗子弹。你会活下去
Well, maybe not
嗯，也许不是
Galan, what the hell are you doing?
伽蓝，你到底在搞什么鬼？
.improvise
。凑合
What's going on there? I need to report the situation now!
那里发生了什么事？ 我现在需要汇报情况！
One more and we'll reach Rahmat
再过一趟我们就能到达拉赫马特
What the hell, Izzy?
到底怎么回事，伊兹？
"(Easy Yesterday)"
“（昨天简单）”
.Okay
。好的
Initial success or miserable failure?
最初的成功还是悲惨的失败？
Initial success
初步成功
.I'm out of ammo. Answer
.我没有弹药了。回答
You mean miserable failure
你的意思是悲惨的失败
Christmas, where are you? .They have taken possession of the explosives
圣诞节，你在哪里？ .他们已经拿到了炸药
They're on the west side .They are heading north
他们在西边 .他们正在向北行驶
Don't let Rahmat leave with explosives .Otherwise many people will die
不要让拉赫马特带着炸药离开 .不然很多人会死
Step up, you losers! We'll go shopping
站起来吧，你们这些失败者！我们去购物
Watch behind you!
小心你身后！
I'll shoot, guys!
我会开枪的，伙计们！
!here
！这里
Be safe!
注意安全！
They are shooting at us!
他们正在向我们开枪！
Don't worry, buddy
别担心，伙计
I will never abandon you
我永远不会放弃你
I can't find a clear angle to shoot
找不到清晰的角度拍摄
-I was exposed to gunfire Damn it, Bernie
-我暴露在枪声中 该死的伯尼
Focus on the mission, Christmas
专注于使命，圣诞节
You're done there!
你已经完成了！
.Listen to him, buddy .Get explosives
.听他说，伙计 .获取炸药
Get the explosives, Lee! !it's a command
拿炸药来，李！ !这是一个命令
No way. I'll save you, you idiot
决不。我会救你的，你这个白痴
!You're welcome
！不客气
Well done, buddy Who will take care of Rahmat?
干得好，伙计 谁来照顾拉赫马特？
Screw it
算了
In memory of Bernie Ross, Chief.
纪念伯尼·罗斯，酋长。
I miss you, Bernie!
我想你，伯尼！
.Everyone is having fun
.大家都玩得很开心
There is an old saying.
有句老话。
“Beware of the evil of an old man participating in an operation The lives of the best young people are being lost.”
“小心老人参与手术的邪恶 最优秀的年轻人的生命正在消失。”
I'm sure they saved Bernie Ross' seat .on the side of the table there for a long time
我确信他们保住了伯尼·罗斯的席位 .在桌子边上放了很长时间
He deserved that seat
他当之无愧地获得这个席位
And he will never stop earning it
他永远不会停止赚钱
He brought out the best in everything .One of us because he was the best of us
他在一切方面都发挥出了最好的一面 .我们中的一员，因为他是我们中最好的
To Bernie
致伯尼
How are you?
你好吗？
.fine
。美好的
No need to pretend, Lee
李没必要假装
Bernie doesn't want to see you sulking like that
伯尼不想看到你那样生闷气
.This is correct
。这是对的
Can I help?
我是否能帮助？
.since you asked
.既然你问了
...I want
...我想
When will we deal with people? Who did this?
我们什么时候才能与人打交道？ 这是谁做的？
You won't deal with anything .You are out of the team
你不会处理任何事情 .你已经脱离队伍了
What does this mean? - It no longer concerns you.
这是什么意思？ - 它不再关心你了。
We don't need you anymore. This is nonsense, Marsh.
我们不再需要你了。 这是胡说八道，马什。
Who's going to run Bernie's team?
谁将领导伯尼的团队？
Jenna)?)
珍娜）？）
Is this some joke?
这是开玩笑吗？
You have disobeyed a direct order from your superior
你违反了上级的直接命令
.which cost us the mission, so you're off the team
.这让我们失去了任务，所以你离开了团队
I tried to save him, Marsh. But you didn't save him.
我试图拯救他，马什。 但你没有救他。
It is our mission and our decision .You are out of the team
这是我们的使命，也是我们的决定 .你已经脱离队伍了
That was Bernie's sacrifice, brother
那是伯尼的牺牲，兄弟
Good death during the mission .This would count
执行任务期间善终 .这个也算
And you robbed him of that
而你却剥夺了他的那个
.You made his sacrifice worthless
.你让他的牺牲变得毫无价值
.(Christmas)
。（圣诞节）
.thanks for the support
。感谢您的支持
.You've bought some time, buddy
.你已经赢得了一些时间，伙计
Bernie hated cover bands
伯尼讨厌翻唱乐队
.I will be in touch
。我会联系你
Nothing Bernie did was worthless
伯尼所做的一切都是毫无价值的
Do you understand, nothing? Calm down, guys.
你明白吗，什么都没有？ 冷静点，伙计们。
Don't talk about Bernie in front of me. Not the right time and place.
别在我面前谈论伯尼。 没有合适的时间和地点。
Please, guys, calm down
请各位冷静下来
"Bernie Ross deleted a contact."
“伯尼·罗斯删除了一个联系人。”
"Classified"
“分类”
"Host in a restaurant"
《餐厅里的主人》
.I know how to host
.我知道如何主持
An influencer's bodyguard On social media
有影响力的保镖 在社交媒体上
“On social media
“在社交媒体上
.I'm going to get a drink
.我去喝一杯
The live broadcast is about to start
直播即将开始
About to start
即将开始
And you look miserable
而你看起来很痛苦
No, no, bye, bye
不不不再见再见
Hey macho, come here
嘿，猛男，过来
.Hey bro, hold the remote
.嘿兄弟，拿着遥控器
.I'm your bodyguard
.我是你的保镖
.I'm here to protect you
.我是来保护你的
Don't hold your remote control
不要握住遥控器
Do you see someone wanting to hurt me?
你看到有人想要伤害我吗？
.maybe
。或许
Whatever, just grab the controller
不管怎样，只要抓住控制器
"Maybe, just shut up."
“也许吧，闭嘴吧。”
How are you doing, you bastards?
你们还好吗，你们这些混蛋？
.I'm here live from my home
.我在家里现场直播
Give some attention to your life Pathetic
给自己的生活多一些关注 可怜的
.Look at these bitches
.看看这些母狗
...Any one
...任何人
No, but any two ...I'm going to fuck
不可以，但是任意两个 ……我要操了
Hey, show some respect to the ladies
嘿，给女士们一点尊重
...I'm live here
...我住在这里
Do you believe this nonsense? .Look at this man
这种鬼话你信吗？ .看看这个人
Who does he think he is?
他以为他是谁？
"Respect ladies!"
“尊重女士！”
I will respect them
我会尊重他们
I will respect them so much that they will lick me Sweat on my testicles
我会非常尊重他们，他们会舔我 我的睾丸出汗了
.damn it
。该死的
Don't bother with him
别理他
Do you know how much I make? Who is this face, stupid?
你知道我赚多少钱吗？ 这张脸是谁啊，笨蛋？
Damn that!
该死的！
"extremely confidential"
“极其机密”
.welcome back
。欢迎回来
.my dear
。亲爱的
You're lucky because I am .I didn't shoot you
你很幸运，因为我是 .我没有开枪打你
.maybe
。或许
Are you reading now?
你现在在读书吗？
What is this?
这是什么？
Are you going somewhere?
你要去某个地方吗？
I'll go catch the guy Who killed Bernie?
我去抓那家伙 谁杀了伯尼？
The only good thing about Bernie's death .is the disclosure of this document
伯尼之死唯一的好处 .是本文件的披露
What does that mean exactly? What is written here?
这到底是什么意思？ 这里写的是什么？
...Good
...好的
Bernie was part of an operation Confidentiality between international agencies
伯尼参与了一次行动 国际机构之间的保密
When the operation failed, he decided all Participants classify the document
当手术失败后，他决定一切 参与者对文档进行分类
Until everyone related to her dies
直到所有与她有关的人都死去
So once Bernie died... The document has been declassified
所以一旦伯尼死了...... 该文件已解密
It gave us an idea of ​​Ocelot's identity
它让我们了解了 Ocelot 的身份
I want to join, I will accompany you
我想加入，我陪你
.I'm sorry
。对不起
.You are not invited
.你没有被邀请
Won't you feel lonely without me?
没有我你不会感到孤独吗？
.both
。两个都
There are many men on the mission
有很多人在执行任务
.I don't have the mood for that
.我没有那个心情
I'll give you one of Hendrix's shows.
我会给你看一场亨德里克斯的表演。
I will use some tricks - Don't start with that -
我会使用一些技巧 - 不要从那开始-
.It started
.开始了
.I've always loved this tattoo
.我一直很喜欢这个纹身
And so is your brother
你的兄弟也是如此
This has always been my favorite seat
这一直是我最喜欢的座位
Well, not like the cheap seats
嗯，不像便宜的座位
You have to be more careful
你必须更加小心
He forced me to do so
他强迫我这样做
Do an old soldier a favor
帮一个老战士一个忙
There are priorities
有优先事项
...I met Bernie
...我遇见了伯尼
When I was laid off from .Special air service
当我被解雇时 .特殊空运服务
I didn't have money, my situation was difficult
我没有钱，我的处境很困难
He bet on me when No one wanted to bet
他在我身上打赌的时候 没有人愿意打赌
We will catch the person who He did this to Bernie
我们会抓住那个人 他对伯尼做了这样的事
.I promise you
。我答应你
.I know I can't accompany you
.我知道我不能陪你
But I want you to take this
但我希望你接受这个
...Good
...好的
I will be sure to convey (Rahmat) your regards
我一定会转达（拉赫马特）您的问候
"Get the signal"
“收到信号”
"Tracking completed"
“追踪完成”
did you understand something? - .I do not know what you say -
你明白什么了吗？ - 。我不知道你在说什么 -
But why do you think it's called Lash? - I don't know, but I would like to know.
但你认为它为什么叫“Lash”？ - 我不知道，但我想知道。
She can flog me whenever she wants
她可以随时鞭打我
.It's bigger than that, my dear
.它比那还要大，亲爱的
No, it's a Chinese bird We use a finger and they run away
不，这是中国鸟 我们用一根手指，他们就逃跑了
...But if it's convenient
……不过如果方便的话
What happened to your ears?
你的耳朵怎么了？
my ears?
我的耳朵？
Everyone knew I was .wrestled in college
每个人都知道我是 .在大学摔跤
This is a common effect .Sports is an ear injury
这是一个常见的效果 .运动是一种耳朵损伤
The cartilage separates from the skin ...and causes a small pocket
软骨与皮肤分离 ...并导致一个小口袋
.I've never seen him so calm
.我从未见过他如此平静
He hasn't spoken anything since his breakup
分手后他就没说过一句话
Do you want to feel it?
你想感受一下吗？
.It's not contagious, I promise you
.它不会传染，我向你保证
South Asian Sea, secret location “CIA
南亚海，秘密地点 “中央情报局
"Thailand"
“泰国”
What's News?
有什么新闻？
I'm looking for Disha
我在寻找迪莎
Disha yunai)?)
迪莎尤奈）？）
from?
从？
A member of Squad 90 From the Thai Special Forces
90小队成员 来自泰国特种部队
Apparently, he has a boat .Moored nearby
显然，他有一条船 .停泊在附近
.I don't know someone like that here
.我在这里不认识这样的人
...But, if he owns a boat
...但是，如果他拥有一艘船
The boats are down there
船就在那里
Not here!
不在这里！
.Thanks for help
。感谢帮助
.Excuse me, my friend
.对不起，我的朋友
Do you know the owner of this boat?
你认识这艘船的主人吗？
I'm looking for someone named Disha
我正在寻找一个叫迪莎的人
I'm sorry, Disha left a long time ago
抱歉，迪莎很久以前就离开了
To where?
去哪里？
To a place of tranquility
到一个宁静的地方
Is he dead?
他死了吗？
.It's common these days
.这几天很常见
!Excuse me
！打扰一下
I can't let you steal This boat, sir!
我不能让你偷东西 先生，这艘船！
What matters to you?
什么对你来说重要？
.It's just a boat, but it's not yours
.这只是一艘船，但它不是你的
Listen, I'll take this boat With or without your consent
听着，我会乘这艘船 无论是否经过您的同意
Why do you have Bernie's ring?
你为什么有伯尼的戒指？
Bernie is dead.
伯尼死了。
And I want this boat to get there For the people who killed him
我想要这艘船到达那里 为了那些杀了他的人
I was looking for Disha
我一直在寻找迪莎
And from what Bernie said about him It will be useful in the coming days
从伯尼对他的评价来看 未来几天会有用
Bernie is dead.
伯尼死了。
I used to be Disha The person you are looking for
我曾经是迪莎 您要找的人
But I left this person behind
但我却把这个人抛在了身后
If what you say is true
如果你说的是真的
I have to avenge Bernie
我必须为伯尼报仇
.definitely
。确实
Okay, everyone, listen up
好吧，大家听着
The ship was hijacked Thai Jintra
船被劫持了 泰国金特拉
In the Andaman Sea, before Our common bond (rahmat).
之前在安达曼海 我们共同的纽带（rahmat）。
Gentra changed course
Gentra改变了路线
It is now sailing towards the coast Vladivostok, Russia.
现在正向海岸航行 俄罗斯符拉迪沃斯托克。
Because of the chaos in Libya
由于利比亚局势混乱
Rahmat possesses nuclear explosives.
拉赫马特拥有核爆炸物。
A barter transaction will take place on board the ship
易货交易将在船上进行
Where they will get the rest of the materials needed to build an active bomb
他们将从哪里获得其余材料 需要建造一枚主动炸弹
Of a nuclear nature, we cannot allow This happens, okay?
具有核性质，我们不能允许 发生这种事，好吗？
We have obtained useful information With Ocelot on board the Gentera
我们获得了有用的信息 Gentera 上有 Ocelot
So maybe this is the only chance To reveal his identity
所以也许这是唯一的机会 为了暴露他的身份
Or her identity
或者她的身份
What did you say?
你说什么？
It may be a woman
可能是一个女人
.or her identity, yes, and we arrest him or her
.或者她的身份，是的，我们逮捕他或她
You know, Bernie's death .revealed the document
你知道，伯尼的死 .泄露文件
Which revealed the person's name Who works with Ocelot
这透露了这个人的名字 谁与 Ocelot 合作
A witness within the witness protection program
证人保护计划中的证人
Russo will explain this topic
Russo 将解释这个话题
His name is Fen Leung Bae
他的名字叫芬良裴
Ocelot's former partner Who will be happy to report on the ocelot
欧斯洛的前搭档 谁会乐意报道豹猫
There's no way out for snitches, is there, Gunner?
告密者没有出路，是吗，枪手？
This is true, there is no salvation for informers
确实如此，告密者无药可救
Now, no need to tell you about The sensitivity of this task
现在，无需告诉您 该任务的敏感性
If the Russians hear that American forces...
如果俄罗斯人听说美国军队...
Not only is it close .But within Russian territory
不仅距离近 .但在俄罗斯境内
It will cause chaos on some level World War III, okay?
一定程度上会造成混乱 第三次世界大战，好吗？
Therefore, this task She does not have any American ID
因此，本次任务 她没有任何美国身份证
.Complete denial of the mission
.完全否认使命
If things get bad, you're on your own
如果事情变得糟糕，你就得靠自己了
...And one last thing
...最后一件事
Since you ruined the last mission ...in Libya without me
自从你毁掉了上次的任务 ...在没有我的利比亚
I will join you this time Isn't that fun?
这次我会加入你 这不是很有趣吗？
Jenna)?)
珍娜）？）
.Okay, that's how it goes
.好吧，事情就是这样
We will carry out this attack as two teams Each team has a separate goal
我们将分两队进行这次攻击 每个团队都有单独的目标
We're on our way to land there
我们正在前往那里着陆的路上
Alpha Team will secure the bridge
Alpha 小组将保护桥梁
While Bravo Team will... .inspect the ship
虽然 Bravo 团队将... .检查船舶
We will be identified and killed or captured On (Ocelot) and (Rahmat).
我们将被认出并被杀或被俘 关于（Ocelot）和（Rahmat）。
We'll get the explosives And nuclear components
我们会找到炸药 以及核部件
And we're out of there, any questions?
我们已经离开那里了，还有什么问题吗？
Is my explanation of the mission different from Bernie's?
我对任务的解释与伯尼的不同吗？
He probably would have said "Let's go"
他可能会说 “我们走吧”
.Okay - .Good -
。好的 -
Let's go
我们走吧
Is this an axe?
这是斧子吗？
No, it's just a snow shovel
不，这只是一把雪铲
This seems reasonable, however It makes sense to you
然而这似乎很合理 这对你来说很有意义
So what's your story?
那么你的故事是什么？
Bernie told me you were leaving Band 90
伯尼告诉我你要走了 乐队 90
.I was the absolute type of killer
.我是绝对的杀手
He's never met anyone faster or better
他从未遇到过更快更好的人
You can kill in a limited number Once upon a time, Christmas
你可以杀死有限的数量 曾几何时，圣诞节
...every time
...每次
It gets easier
变得更容易
.It becomes a drug for pain, for happiness
.它成为止痛、快乐的药物
And for love
并且为了爱情
...with every person you kill
...你杀死的每一个人
You will lose more of yourself
你会失去更多的自己
I should have stopped sooner .to lose everything
我应该早点停下来 .失去一切
I think I will benefit from my experience now
我想我现在会从我的经验中受益
It's so quiet, something's wrong!
这么安静，好像有什么事情！
Easy Day and Marsh will accompany me.
Easy Day 和 Marsh 会陪我。
The rest will head to the starboard beam
其余的将前往右舷横梁
What's the starboard keel again?
右舷龙骨又是什么？
In the army we used to say .right, left
在军队里我们常说 。右左
Starboard then
那么右舷
- The gate is on the left and the crossbar is in the back. I got it.
- 大门在左侧，横杆在后面。 我得到了它。
.let's move
。让我们继续前进
I have a bad feeling about this. Yes, where is everyone? -
我对此有一种不好的预感。 是的，大家都在哪里？ -
The nuclear bomb definitely exists .on board
核弹肯定存在 。在船上
Well, listen, I have bad news
好吧，听着，我有坏消息
They already have uranium With nuclear warheads
他们已经有了铀 带有核弹头
The ship is currently on board .Active nuclear bomb
目前该船已在船上 .主动核弹
We are about to reach the bridge
我们即将到达大桥
.It's like a ghost town
.这就像一座鬼城
.Put the weapon down now
.现在放下武器
What a mess it would be here
这里会多么混乱啊
"Libya first, now this?"
“首先是利比亚，现在是这个？”
Both times, someone... .He knew we were coming
两次，都有人... .他知道我们要来
My information was correct. Your information was crap.
我的信息是正确的。 你的信息很垃圾。
.You are a fool yourself
.你自己就是个傻子
.Information may have leaked
.信息可能已泄露
We don't know you. We have verified it -
我们不认识你。 我们已经核实过了——
So maybe she's your new friend. Damn you, Gunner.
所以也许她是你的新朋友。 该死的，枪手。
You've already sold us on that one Mission in Vilnius
你已经把那件事卖给了我们 在维尔纽斯的使命
Did you think I would forget about it?
你以为我会忘记这件事吗？
.Someone really sold us out
.有人真的出卖了我们
what about your friend?
你的朋友呢？
.You sold it to be at the top
.你卖掉它是为了达到顶峰
.Calm down, she won't do that
.冷静点，她不会这么做的
Why? To be at the top? - .damn it -
为什么？成为顶端？ - 。该死的 -
Maybe the silent person in the corner
也许是角落里沉默的人
What's the matter, Galan? Did the cat eat your tongue, my dear?
伽兰，怎么了？ 亲爱的，猫吃了你的舌头吗？
Yes, he's hiding something!
是的，他有事隐瞒！
.I never trusted him
.我从来不相信他
Translation and modification || Muhammad Al Nuaimi and Dr. Ali Talal
翻译及修改 ||穆罕默德·阿尔·努埃米 (Muhammad Al Nuaimi) 和阿里·塔拉勒 (Ali Talal) 博士
Who is the leader? - .I am the leader -
谁是领导者？ - .我是领导者-
Take him
带他
Screw it
算了
.here we are
。我们到了
.it's time
。是时候了
I'll go first, I'll let you know when .Be safe to follow me
我先走了，到时候通知你 .请安全地跟随我
.I'll stop here
.我就停在这里
You might be of use to me. .I can not do that -
你也许对我有用。 。我不能这样做 -
If I allow my nature The old is to be revealed
如果我允许我的本性 旧事即将揭晓
I don't know if I was Able to hide her second.
我不知道我是不是 能够隐藏她的第二个。
.I understand
。我明白
It was meant to be There's a bloodbath here!
这是命中注定的 这里发生了一场血战！
where are you?
你在哪里？
My shift is over, I'm going downstairs
我的值班结束了，我要下楼了
.Don't move, turn around slowly
.别动，慢慢转身
Be clear my friend?
说清楚点吗朋友？
I don't move? Or turn around slowly?
我不动？还是慢慢转身？
!Turn around!
！回转！
.very slowly
。非常缓慢地
!Oh, my God
！我的天啊
Colin, you scared me, my friend.
科林，你吓到我了，我的朋友。
(Colin)? Who is Colin?
（科林）？科林是谁？
Do not shoot, you must avoid the evil of that.
不要开枪，你必须避免它的邪恶。
You may get shot in the hand.
您的手可能会被击中。
Perfect timing, Mr. Marsh.
完美的时机，马什先生。
(Marsh)?
（沼泽）？
The mission was a setup The secret of our information is one person.
任务是一个设置 我们的信息的秘密是一个人。
My requests are easy.
我的要求很简单。
Prisoner exchange.
交换俘虏。
I want your prisoner, Ben Leung Bae.
我想要你的囚犯本良裴。
A dear friend of my friend.
我朋友的好朋友。
If you don't meet that...
如果你不满足那个...
Mr. Marsh will show how serious I am.
马什先生会表明我是多么认真。
So what will it be, Russo?
那会是什么，鲁索？
I don't have the power.
我没有权力。
I know you don't have the power.
我知道你没有这个权力。
But...
但...
I know someone who owns it.
我认识一个拥有它的人。
Let's go shoot down the last fake plane.
我们去击落最后一架假飞机吧。
(Mercies).
（怜悯）。
You cunning snake.
你这条狡猾的蛇。
I can provide power for you.
我可以为你提供力量。
Ben Leung Bai is in your prison.
Ben Leung Bai 在你的监狱里。
Your contact is Donald Ullman.
您的联系人是唐纳德·厄尔曼。
Approval number: 2-2-5-7-9.
批准文号：2-2-5-7-9。
Gently and without messing around.
轻轻地，不乱七八糟。
You will decide whether this is the case Whether the latest is forgotten or remembered.
您将决定是否属于这种情况 最新的是否被遗忘或记住。
"Find a signal"
“寻找信号”
"Search complete"
“搜索完成”
Look at this man I adore him and he is my role model.
看看这个人 我崇拜他，他是我的榜样。
I will respect them enough.
我会足够尊重他们。
I hope you meet him one day.
我希望有一天你能见到他。
This knife is not yours.
这把刀不是你的。
Where are my comrades?
我的战友们在哪里？
Sir, we may have a problem.
先生，我们可能遇到了问题。
Contact with Payton and Tuck has been lost.
与佩顿和塔克失去了联系。
Second floor, room 657.
二楼657室。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
(Gunner).
（炮手）。
What?
什么？
This is what I like to use.
这是我喜欢用的。
Answer me, Tuck.
回答我，塔克。
Maybe there's an intruder on board the ship. Check the work of all staff.
也许船上有入侵者。 检查所有员工的工作。
What?
什么？
Tuck can't respond at the moment.
塔克暂时无法回应。
It's a little stressful.
有点压力。
where is he?
他在哪里？
Someone committed a sin and kept you alive.
有人犯了罪，让你活了下来。
But I came to care about this matter.
但我开始关心这件事了。
Look who's striving to be a hero.
看看谁在努力成为英雄。
What a great thing to have you join us.
您加入我们真是太好了。
If you hope you will solve the problem In Libya, I am sorry that you are late.
如果你希望你能解决问题 在利比亚，我很抱歉你迟到了。
My men are coming to get you.
我的人来抓你了。
It's up to me if you die young.
你是否英年早逝由我决定。
Just like I did to your friend in Libya.
就像我对你在利比亚的朋友所做的那样。
To correct, he was not my friend.
更正一下，他不是我的朋友。
Rather, he was my brother.
相反，他是我的兄弟。
Then you can bring your army.
然后你就可以带上你的军队了。
Bring what men you have I will take care of them one by one.
带上你有的男人 我会一一照顾他们。
Whenever I reach you
每当我到达你身边
I will make sure of the only way To get off this ship.
我会确定唯一的方法 才能离开这艘船。
That it's broken into pieces.
它被打碎成碎片了。
Don't shoot, it's a bomb.
别开枪，这是炸弹。
Okay.
好的。
Do you see the intruder, Pavel?
你看到入侵者了吗，帕维尔？
Yes sir. - Where is it located?
是的先生。 - 它位于哪里？
Ground floor corridor.
一楼走廊。
ship surface. What?
船舶表面。 什么？
Where are my comrades?
我的战友们在哪里？
Sir, we may have a problem.
先生，我们可能遇到了问题。
Contact with Payton and Tuck has been lost.
与佩顿和塔克失去了联系。
Second floor, room 657.
二楼657室。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
(Gunner).
（炮手）。
What?
什么？
This is what I like to use.
这是我喜欢用的。
Answer me, Tuck.
回答我，塔克。
Maybe there's an intruder on board the ship. Check the work of all staff.
也许船上有入侵者。 检查所有员工的工作。
What?
什么？
Tuck can't respond at the moment.
塔克暂时无法回应。
It's a little stressful.
有点压力。
where is he?
他在哪里？
Someone committed a sin and kept you alive.
有人犯了罪，让你活了下来。
But I came to care about this matter.
但我开始关心这件事了。
Look who's striving to be a hero.
看看谁在努力成为英雄。
What a great thing to have you join us.
您加入我们真是太好了。
If you hope you will solve the problem In Libya, I am sorry that you are late.
如果你希望你能解决问题 在利比亚，我很抱歉你迟到了。
My men are coming to get you.
我的人来抓你了。
It's up to me if you die young.
你是否英年早逝由我决定。
Just like I did to your friend in Libya.
就像我对你在利比亚的朋友所做的那样。
To correct, he was not my friend.
更正一下，他不是我的朋友。
Rather, he was my brother.
相反，他是我的兄弟。
Then you can bring your army.
然后你就可以带上你的军队了。
Bring what men you have I will take care of them one by one.
带上你有的男人 我会一一照顾他们。
Whenever I reach you
每当我到达你身边
I will make sure of the only way To get off this ship.
我会确定唯一的方法 才能离开这艘船。
That it's broken into pieces.
它被打碎成碎片了。
Don't shoot, it's a bomb.
别开枪，这是炸弹。
Okay.
好的。
Do you see the intruder, Pavel?
你看到入侵者了吗，帕维尔？
Yes sir. - Where is it located?
是的先生。 - 它位于哪里？
Ground floor corridor.
一楼走廊。
ship surface. What?
船舶表面。 什么？
Officers dining room, Third deck.
军官餐厅、 第三甲板。
Have a nice trip, my dear.
祝你旅途愉快，亲爱的。
It's in the stern of the ship.
它在船尾。
what are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
I thought you were done with this life.
我以为你已经结束了这一生。
Letting Bernie's friend pass away Life is an insult to his memory.
让伯尼的朋友去世 生活是对他记忆的侮辱。
I like your look.
我喜欢你的外表。
I thank you.
我谢谢你。
- Let's do it. Good.
- 我们开始做吧。 好的。
I think everything is closed here.
我想这里一切都关门了。
- Yeah, I think that's nicely welded too. - Okay, so what next?
- 是的，我认为这也焊接得很好。 - 好吧，那么接下来怎么办？
- “Drainage water” system. What?
- “排水”系统。 什么？
Bilge water system.
舱底水系统。
In emergency cases, the water is drained In dry areas of the ship.
紧急情况下，水被排掉 船上干燥区域。
If we open it, we will be able to get out.
如果我们打开它，我们就能出去。
Let's open it.
让我们打开它。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
- He's not moving. - No, it must be wet.
- 他没有动。 - 不，它一定是湿的。
What? -If it is wet, it will open.
什么？ - 如果潮湿，它会打开。
-Is anyone urinating? - I'm going to pee.
-有人小便吗？ - 我要去撒尿。
I haven't peed since we parachuted out here.
自从我们在这里跳伞以来我就没尿过尿。
My privacy please.
请保护我的隐私。
The greatness of the tongue.
舌头的伟大。
It is the only bone in the body Man is not related to another greatness.
它是人体唯一的骨头 人与其他伟大事物无关。
It's in the mouth here You can't talk without it.
就在这儿嘴里 没有它你就无法说话。
But I'll take out the tongue bone From Rahmat's lower mouth with my own hands
但我会取出舌骨 从 Rahmat 的下口用我自己的双手
He put it in his friend's ass
他把它放进了他朋友的屁股里
I will make them apologize They are soaked in their own blood.
我会让他们道歉 他们浑身都沾满了自己的鲜血。
Bernie was my role model.
伯尼是我的榜样。
I can't speak.
我不能说话。
Because my mind is full These cruel illusions.
因为我的脑子已经满了 这些残酷的幻想。
And imagine I will turn it into a horrific reality.
想象一下我会把它变成一个可怕的现实。
It's better that you come back and not talk.
你回来最好不要说话。
I finished.
我完成了。
Are there buyers?
有买家吗？
Will this lead us to The man who killed Bernie?
这会导致我们 杀死伯尼的人？
Okay.
好的。
I will take his revenge.
我会为他报仇。
It turns out he loves the Golden Shower.
原来他喜欢黄金雨。
Leung Bai is coming for you now.
梁白现在来找你了。
I'm looking forward to getting my team back to life.
我期待着让我的团队恢复生机。
certainly.
当然。
What is a person worth without his word?
一个人如果没有他的言语，还有什么价值呢？
Be prepared to exchange.
做好交换的准备。
Get out!
出去！
- This way. Good.
- 这边走。 好的。
- Your companions will be happy to see you. - Probably not.
- 你的同伴会很高兴见到你。 - 可能不会。
Jenna will have to Admitting that she needs me.
珍娜将不得不 承认她需要我。
- Count to three. Good.
- 数到三。 好的。
three.
三。
- There's no one here. both.
- 这里没人。 两个都。
Where did they go?
他们去哪儿了？
Do I smell urine?
我闻到尿味了吗？
Okay.
好的。
We will remain calm until now It's time to make noise.
直到现在我们都会保持冷静 是时候发出声音了。
Lie down.
躺。
Is it time to hype?
是时候炒作了吗？
You are the one who should Lay down, man.
你是那个应该 躺下，伙计。
So what?
所以呢？
Don't forget that we are mercenaries.
别忘了我们是雇佣兵。
Don't tell me.
别告诉我。
You are so happy to see me.
你很高兴见到我。
In practice, you are no longer from Mercenaries, Christmas.
实际上，你不再来自 雇佣兵, 圣诞节.
Especially you.
尤其是你。
gladly. - As was just said.
乐意。 ——正如刚才所说。
- Excellent timing. - (Easy Day).
- 时机绝佳。 -（简单的一天）。
Christmas).
圣诞节）。
Is this my axe?
这是我的斧头吗？
Okay. -Do you like it?
好的。 -你喜欢它？
-I'm starting to adapt to it. - What delayed you?
-我开始适应了。 - 是什么耽误了你？
Do you think I will believe it? That you gave me your knife?
你觉得我会相信吗？ 你把刀给了我？
Did you give her your knife? - They say the romance is over.
你把刀给她了吗？ - 他们说浪漫已经结束了。
He put a tracking device in the knife.
他在刀里放了一个追踪装置。
It's all part of the plan, sorry.
抱歉，这都是计划的一部分。
I feel exploited.
我感觉自己被剥削了。
Okay, let's go.
好吧，我们走吧。
Stay behind us, Gunner.
留在我们身后，枪手。
I like your hair.
我喜欢你的头发。
- Who is your new friend? - (Disha).
- 谁是你的新朋友？ -（迪莎）。
An old friend of Bernie's. He has a status with those closest to him.
伯尼的老朋友。 他在最亲近的人中享有一定的地位。
Any friend of Bernie's is fine. As concerned as I am.
伯尼的任何朋友都很好。 和我一样担心。
Rahmat kidnapped Marsh.
拉赫马特绑架了马什。
You should stay with Toll Road.
你应该留在收费公路。
I want you to take a look at something.
我想让你看一些东西。
This is a huge bomb.
这是一颗巨大的炸弹。
The explosives we didn't get.
我们没有得到炸药。
What is this?
这是什么？
Can you disable it?
你可以禁用它吗？
Prepared to explode in 27 minutes and reinforced From neutralization and it has silver keys.
27分钟内准备爆炸并加固 从中和它有银钥匙。
There is only one way to disable it: Find the key to disable the wireless connection.
只有一种方法可以禁用它： 找到禁用无线连接的密钥。
This is its last line of defence.
这是它的最后一道防线。
The key is short-term and it is... He owns it on board this ship.
关键是短期的，而且... 他在这艘船上拥有它。
- It is (mercy).
- 这是（怜悯）。
- Who is (Rahmat)? - He's the one who killed Bernie.
- 谁是（拉赫马特）？ - 他是杀死伯尼的人。
We must have entered a protected area.
我们一定是进入了保护区。
They camouflaged the ship and made it As if it were an American aircraft carrier.
他们伪装了这艘船并制造了它 就好像它是一艘美国航空母舰。
With a nuclear bomb equipped To blow up the Russian coast.
配备核弹 炸毁俄罗斯海岸。
This will spark a third world war.
这将引发第三次世界大战。
The clock is ticking, let's take action.
时间紧迫，让我们采取行动吧。
The new place is the deck of the ship.
新的地方是船的甲板。
Now it's all about stopping the bomb.
现在最重要的是阻止炸弹爆炸。
We eliminate (Rahmat) forever.
我们永远消除（Rahmat）。
Can you make for us? Something loud and wild?
你能为我们做吗？ 有什么吵闹而狂野的东西吗？
Does the Pope defecate in the forest?
教皇在森林里排便吗？
No, the Pope doesn't defecate in the woods.
不，教皇不会在树林里排便。
Not near a bear Why do you say these things?
不靠近熊 你为什么说这些话？
what is that?
那是什么？
Damn, it's a bomb.
该死，这是一颗炸弹。
Screw it!
算了！
No problem.
没问题。
You're welcome.
不客气。
It's great to be back.
很高兴回来。
I'm with you.
我和你在一起。
I thank you.
我谢谢你。
You bastard!
你这个混蛋！
I will take care of him.
我会照顾他的。
(Tulle).
（薄纱）。
We need help.
我们需要帮助。
Can you kiss the wound to heal?
你能亲吻伤口让伤口愈合吗？
Maybe later, but I'm busy right now.
也许以后会吧，但我现在很忙。
I'll handle it.
我会处理的。
Ready for prisoner exchange.
准备交换战俘。
Three minutes to land.
三分钟降落。
Waiting for the exchange.
等待兑换。
We continue as planned.
我们继续按计划进行。
What's the matter, Rahmat?
怎么了，拉赫马特？
I see you like to play with knives.
我看你很喜欢玩刀。
I don't play anymore.
我不玩了。
Give me the deactivation key We'll get the whole thing over with.
给我停用密钥 我们会把整个事情搞定的。
Come and get him, hero.
快来抓住他吧，英雄。
Is this your strongest?
这是你最强的吗？
both.
两个都。
This is my strongest.
这是我最强的。
Is that all?
这就是全部？
Okay.
好的。
Where is the kill switch?
终止开关在哪里？
You bastard!
你这个混蛋！
I don't have the kill switch.
我没有终止开关。
My boss has it.
我的老板有它。
(Ocelot).
（豹猫）。
Ben Leung Bai has arrived.
白本良来了。
He is the witness who can Getting to know the ocelot.
他是证人，可以 认识豹猫。
- Hello, Bay. no. Oh, my God.
- 你好，贝。 不。我的天啊。
no. - Goodbye, Bay.
不。 - 再见，贝。
Marsh is an ocelot.
马什是一只豹猫。
He had the key to disabling everything...
他有一把钥匙，可以让一切都失效……
This is for Bernie.
这是给伯尼的。
How long until the explosion?
距离爆炸还有多久？
12 minutes.
12分钟。
Well, we have 12 minutes to explode The ship is like a firework...
好吧，我们有 12 分钟的时间来爆炸 船就像烟花一样......
Marsh, I don't think you need it anymore.
马什，我认为你不再需要它了。
Hey, Christmas.
嘿，圣诞节。
You are like genital warts.
你就像尖锐湿疣。
It pops up when he doesn't want it There is no one in her and she refuses to leave.
当他不想要的时候它就会弹出 她身边没有人，她拒绝离开。
You got something I need, Marsh.
你有我需要的东西，马什。
I will come to get him.
我会来接他。
I think you understand
我想你明白
This device is just the thing Which prevents a third world war.
这个设备就是这样 这阻止了第三次世界大战。
A conflict that will be fatal to many.
一场对许多人来说将是致命的冲突。
Which would be an order Very comfortable for someone.
这将是一个订单 对某人来说非常舒服。
And that person will be me.
而那个人就是我。
The mercenaries will bear all the blame.
所有的罪责都将由雇佣兵承担。
So enjoy the show.
所以尽情享受这个表演吧。
-Kill them all. - Take cover.
-杀光他们。 - 寻找掩护。
They all bowed down.
他们都跪下了。
We need to get off this ship Otherwise we'll be French fries.
我们需要离开这艘船 否则我们就变成炸薯条了。
The pizza looks so opposite Excellent idea now.
披萨看起来很相反 现在真是个好主意。
We'll never get out of blast range.
我们永远无法脱离爆炸范围。
We won't make it in time.
我们来不及了。
Hey, don't die on my shift.
嘿，别死在我值班的时候。
We have to leave, he's bleeding.
我们必须离开，他在流血。
An idea came to my mind.
我想到了一个主意。
Can you take my boat?
你能坐我的船吗？
He is behind us.
他在我们后面。
It's a good idea.
是个好主意。
- Next time we'll start with that. Okay.
- 下次我们就从这个开始。 好的。
Gunner, cover us with a shot Fire, we're on our way out.
炮手，用射击掩护我们 火了，我们要出去了。
I'll handle that. They opened fire.
我会处理的。 他们开枪了。
I'll come back and we'll meet at the back of the ship.
我会回来，我们会在船尾见面。
Grenade.
手榴弹。
Let's get moving.
让我们行动起来吧。
I saw the girl on the other side.
我看到了对面的那个女孩。
There's no one on the bridge.
桥上空无一人。
Start searching the ship.
开始搜寻这艘船。
You're next, Toll Road.
下一个就是你，收费公路。
Now it's your turn, Galan.
现在轮到你了，加兰。
Come forward.
挺身而出。
What?
什么？
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
The task has priority.
任务有优先级。
I have to turn this ship around.
我必须调转这艘船。
Maybe sacrifice can do that.
也许牺牲可以做到这一点。
The decision is his decision.
这个决定就是他的决定。
Disha, you have to hurry or else The Toll Road will be black.
迪莎，你得快点，否则 收费公路将变黑。
Check into the ward. They're walking around.
进病房检查。他们正在四处走动。
Anchor.
锚。
Bring the lifeboats here.
把救生艇带到这里。
Commander, we are returning to the sea.
指挥官，我们要返回大海了。
Come on, hurry up.
快一点。
These are genital warts.
这些是尖锐湿疣。
Kill him.
杀了他。
More boats.
更多的船。
We need to get the ship back on course Go up to the bridge and fix it.
我们需要让船回到航线 走到桥上并修复它。
But sir...
但是先生...
"Sir" what?
“先生”什么？
The bomb will explode and we can't get up...
炸弹会爆炸，我们起不来……
What do you think about the promotion?
您对促销有何看法？
Go up to the bridge.
上桥去。
Kill him.
杀了他。
Come to the bridge, hurry!
到了桥上，快点！
Looks like we'll meet again Soon, Bernie.
看来我们还会再见面 很快，伯尼。
Christmas).
圣诞节）。
I'm here, Marsh.
我在这里，马什。
I see you called in the cavalry.
我看到你召集了骑兵。
You can't get rid of me.
你无法摆脱我。
All the fun is in the trying.
所有的乐趣都在于尝试。
Would you like to come down here and meet face to face?
您愿意来这里面对面交流吗？
Man versus man.
人与人之间。
Like the old days
就像过去一样
Filled with fun.
充满了乐趣。
I can't wait.
我等不及了。
Don't you dare move.
你不敢动。
I'm coming to you.
我正在往你的地方去。
Bernie tried to expose me 20 years ago but he failed.
伯尼试图揭露我 20年前，但他失败了。
But you are a skilled soldier.
但你是一名熟练的士兵。
You are a brilliant soldier.
你是一名出色的士兵。
But this is beyond your capabilities.
但这超出了你的能力范围。
This matter...
这件事...
This is an advanced stage.
这是一个高级阶段。
Bernie was proud of you.
伯尼为你感到骄傲。
You can tell him yourself.
你可以亲自告诉他。
Because you are about to join him.
因为你即将加入他。
What a wonderful thing.
多么美妙的事情啊。
Look what Santa brought me.
看看圣诞老人给我带来了什么。
What is this?
这是什么？
(Bernie)?
（伯尼）？
I'm tired of traditional methods.
我厌倦了传统的方法。
You almost killed me.
你差点杀了我。
You're welcome.
不客气。
faster.
快点。
- What exactly is going on here? -Hang on.
- 这里到底发生了什么？ -不挂断。
- Where is the bomb? - Her matter is settled.
- 炸弹在哪里？ ——她的事情已经解决了。
Wait, you're dead.
等等，你死定了。
what is going on? -I'm a little busy.
到底是怎么回事？ -我有点忙。
So what's the story?
那么故事是怎样的呢？
25 years ago they had an operation Dismissed and eight employees were dismissed
25年前他们做了一次手术 被解雇，8名员工被解雇
And you had to visit a wall To discover a document of a certain type.
你必须参观一堵墙 发现某种类型的文档。
I brought Marsh out of hiding to... I can prove it's an ocelot.
我把马什从藏身之处带出来... 我可以证明这是一只豹猫
Why did you hide it from us?
你为什么向我们隐瞒？
I did this task in the hope that... You live and that's why it was personal.
我做这个任务是希望... 你活着，这就是为什么它是个人的。
That is it.
这就对了。
I need a drink.
我需要喝一杯。
Me too.
我也是。
-You order drinks. - I'm broke.
-你点饮料。 - 我破产了。
You had more fun dying.
你死得更开心。
It's great to spend time with you again.
很高兴再次与您共度时光。
But you can take a shower.
但你可以洗澡。
In memory of Bernie Ross, Chief.
纪念伯尼·罗斯，酋长。
- Toll Road, you owe me $20. - Maybe you don't need glasses.
- 收费公路，你欠我 20 美元。 - 也许你不需要眼镜。
It's okay.
没关系。
Good.
好的。
In the health of my friends who do not They never give up in life.
为了那些没有的朋友们的健康 他们在生活中从不放弃。
Cheers!
干杯!
- For life.
- 为了一生。
Good health, comrades.
祝同志们身体健康。
How about the cliche sentence on On the ship, Christmas?
陈词滥调的句子怎么样 在船上，圣诞节？
You mustn't do that again, Toll Road.
收费公路，你不能再这样做了。
Maybe my sacrifice now.
也许我现在的牺牲。
Fuck you.
去你的。
Stop making life difficult It's amazing, my love.
别让生活变得困难 太棒了，我的爱人。
amazing.
惊人的。
- Everyone is jealous of you because you are the most handsome. I know that.
- 每个人都嫉妒你，因为你最帅。 我知道。
Oh the beauty of love.
哦，爱情的美丽。
Hello, Toll Road.
你好，收费公路。
truly?
真的吗？
Bernie Ross is back from the dead.
伯尼·罗斯死而复生。
You are the only one who can get out From hell without being scratched.
你是唯一能出去的人 来自地狱而不被刮伤。
You are like a legendary bird rising from the ashes.
你就像一只从灰烬中重生的传奇之鸟。
- That's how you are... one minute.
- 你就是这样的... 等一下。
I am calm and talk to my role model Can you give me some space, Easy Day?
我冷静地与我的榜样交谈 Easy Day，你能给我一些空间吗？
Hey, Galan, do you have a minute of your time?
嘿，加兰，你有时间吗？
certainly. -I have a small question.
当然。 -我有一个小问题。
Help yourself.
帮助自己。
Here he is.
他在这里。
- A scrap ring. -I missed this.
- 一个废戒指。 -我错过了这个。
thank you my friend. Sorry.
谢谢，我的朋友。 对不起。
I should know.
我应该知道。
Body of it?
其本体？
exactly.
确切地。
Have you ever wondered what... Happened to Jumbo Shrim?
你有没有想过什么... 发生了巨型虾吗？
Warning, the ground is very close.
警告，地面非常接近。
Warning, there is no landing strip here.
警告，这里没有着陆跑道。
Has risen.
已升起。
I did.
我做到了。
Yes offcourse.
是的，当然。
Translation and modification || Muhammad Al Nuaimi and Dr. Ali Talal
翻译及修改 ||穆罕默德·阿尔·努埃米 (Muhammad Al Nuaimi) 和阿里·塔拉勒 (Ali Talal) 博士